1964. When America was at war with itself.
Mississippi Burning is a drama, crime, mystery film directed by Alan Parker.
Two FBI agents investigating the murder of civil rights workers during the 60s seek to breach the
conspiracy of silence in a small Southern town where segregation divides black and white.
The younger agent trained in FBI school runs up against the
small town ways of his partner, a former sheriff.
Agent Rupert Anderson, played by Gene Hackman.
Agent Alan Ward, played by Willem Dafoe.
Mrs. Pell, played by Frances McDormand.
Deputy Clinton Pell, played by Brad Dourif.
Mayor Tilman, played by R. Lee Ermey.
Sheriff Stuckey, played by Gailard Sartain.
Mississippi Burning is a 1988 American crime thriller film directed by Alan Parker and written by Chris Gerolmo that is loosely
based on the 1964 investigation into the murders of Chaney, Goodman, and Schwerner in Neshoba County, Mississippi.
It stars Gene Hackman and Willem Dafoe as two FBI agents investigating the disappearance of three civil rights activists in fictional
Jessup County, Mississippi, who are met with hostility by the town's residents, local police, and the Ku Klux Klan.
Gerolmo began writing the script in 1986 after researching the 1964
murders of James Chaney, Andrew Goodman and Michael Schwerner.
He and producer Frederick Zollo presented it to Orion
Pictures, and the studio hired Parker to direct.
The writer and director had disputes over the script, and
Orion allowed Parker to make uncredited rewrites.
The film was shot in a number of locations in Mississippi and
Alabama, with principal photography from March to May 1988.
On release, Mississippi Burning was criticized by activists involved in the civil rights movement
and the families of Chaney, Goodman and Schwerner for its fictionalization of events.
Critical reaction was generally positive, with praise for the cinematography
and the performances of Hackman, Dafoe and Frances McDormand.
The film grossed $34.6 million in North America
against a production budget of $15 million.
It received seven Academy Award nominations, including Best
Picture, and won for Best Cinematography.
The film explores themes of suicide, sheriff, police, funeral, ku klux klan.
The tone is intense and lighthearted and emotional.